Berel Levy

Data & Software Engineer

NYC Metro Area (917) 679-8518 github.com/berellevy berellevy.com/

Profile

User-oriented software developer with 5+ years developing powerful internal tooling to solve business problems. Holistic, methodical, and detailed professional that excels at working with others to solve concrete UX problems while building strong relationships.

Skills

Frontend	Backend	Cloud Computing & Storage
AlpineJSCSSHTMXJavaScriptReactUI Design	 Celery Django Docker FastAPI MySQL Nginx Python Ruby 	 AWS EC2 AWS IAM AWS RDS DigitalOcean Google Cloud Platform (GCP)
Client Platforms	Data Analytics	IDEs & Source Control
LinuxMacOSWindows	BigQueryPowerBIRedisSQL	Microsoft Visual Studio CodeGitHub

Relevant Experience

Full Stack Software Engineer

July 2021 - Present

Allin1Ship, Brooklyn, NY

- Sole software developer building, maintaining, and enhancing custom internal tooling.
- Developed an automated bill processing system in Django, MySQL and React that pulls data
 from multiple sources, validates and refactors it, and computes complex calculations to
 correctly bill customers for 1000s of shipments each week. Built both the front- and backend of
 this custom product in under 18 months while keeping the original script running with no
 downtime. Deployed to AWS.
- Designed and built a shipping quote and labeling API in **FastAPI**, **Docker**, **Nginx** and **MySQL** and connecting ecommerce websites, shipping software, and carrier's API that produces printable labels in <200 ms. Stood up full-featured sandbox and production environments, wrote comprehensive documentation, and set up automated end-to-end testing, including load and regression testing Deployed to **DigitalOcean**.
- Developed custom quoting and pricing automation for customer acquisition Django, MySQL,
 htmx and AlpineJS that shows customers and sales personnel the best savings while managing

and rationalizing inconsistent data formats. Integrated rate matrices into complex calculations to output a filterable CSV for internal and external audiences. Deployed to **DigitalOcean**.

Software Engineer

Jan. - June 2021

Sales Enablement Specialist

Jan. 2017 - Feb. 2019

M&D Door, NYC

- Improved the company's ability to land multi-company deals by developing a custom filtering plugin that augmented the CRM's search facets.
- Developed a sales intelligence platform and data pipeline using PowerBI that analyzed bids for more informed analyses, ensuring the sales team did not waste time bidding on unlikely-to-win projects. The custom dashboard, powered by the data pipeline, presented the transformed CRM data into user-friendly insights that solved visibility gaps in the sales funnel.
- Built an insights dashboard that solved visibility gaps. Created an Excel-based software that improved follow-up rates.
- Managed a sales team.

Projects

Job App Filler | [TypeScript, React]

Job App Filler is a Chrome extension that auto-fills fields on tedious applicant tracking systems such as Workday and ICIMS. Developed, tested, and documented extension, including creating user-friendly videos. (repo)

Other Experience

Territory Manager Feb. - June 2020

New York Wholesale Intercom, NYC

Sales Professional Dec. 2019 - Feb. 2020

Catapult Lighting, NYC

Sales Professional March 2019 - Feb. 2020

Fermax USA, Brooklyn, NY

Retail Leasing March 2015 - Nov. 2016

Uptown Flats, NYC

Education

Certificate, Full Stack Web Development

2020

Flatiron School, New York, NY

Developed FauxMeaux, a social media app that introduced a novel advertising model. ReadMe, code, and demo videos at: https://github.com/berellevy/fauxmeaux_frontend

Interests

Lego horology (clockmaking); hiking; freestyle FPV drones.